Kirkman mss., 1836-1875 LMC 2336
Lilly Library
Kirkman mss.
1836-1875
Lilly Library
Wallace, David, 1799-1859
Wright, Joseph A. (Joseph Albert), 1810-1867
LMC 2336
1 Box 1 standard
The Kirkman mss., 1836-1875, consists of the papers of Joseph J. Kirkman, 1809-1879, a farmer, businessman, and sheriff of Gibson County, Indiana.
Box 1
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 1989-1990
Biographical Note
Joseph Jackson Kirkman, 1809-1879, was a farmer, businessman, and sheriff of Gibson County, Indiana. He was born on September 9, 1809 in Christian County, Kentucky. His father moved the family to Gibson County, Indiana in 1813. As a young man, Joseph J. Kirkman became a farmer and owned one of the first brickyards in the county. He is most known for holding the position of Sheriff of Gibson County for many years. Kirkman married Jane Smith Denny on July 29, 1828, and together they had nine children. He died on March 9, 1879.
Scope and Content Note
The Kirkman mss., 1836-1875, are the papers of Joseph J. Kirkman, 1809-1879, a farmer, businessman, and sheriff of Gibson County, Indiana. Included are papers relating to the flatboat trade; a butcher's account book, June 27, 1838-Feb. 1, 1841; bills for merchandise purchased by Kirkman, June 15, 1846-November 23, 1875, from Devin & Franch, Lewis Evans & Co., George N. Jerauld, James Thomas Embree, administrator of the estate of Joseph Devin, G. B. & S. J. Bingham and J. Jennings; some Civil War letters dated from June 23, 1862-November 2, 1864; a group of deeds of land and land grants in Gibson County; some papers of Samuel Hall; and other miscellaneous papers.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged following original order.
Voyages and travels; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Indiana -- History; Land grants--United States; Kirkman, Joseph, 1809-1879
- Flatboat trade papers, 1846-1850
  Scope and Contents
  The flatboat papers consist of letters written by Kirkman to Joseph Devin, merchant of Gibson County, who sent a large number of flatboats to the New Orleans market in the years 1832 to 1850, dealing with the flatboat business, and two statements of accounts rendered to Kirkman, May 28 and June 11, 1847, by Martin & Stockwell of New Orleans for the sale of produce received by flatboat.
- Butcher's account book, June 27, 1838-Feb. 1, 1841
- Bills, June 15, 1846-November 23, 1875
  Covers merchandise purchases by Kirkman from Devin & Franch, Lewis Evans & Co., George N. Jerauld, James Thomas Embree, administrator of the estate of Joseph Devin, G. B. & S. J. Bingham and J. Jennings.
- Civil War letters, June 23, 1862-November 2, 1864
  The Civil War letters are from Robert Featherstone at Batesville, Arkansas; William Snow; John Watkins; George D. Kirkman; John Orr; Samuel Blacketer; and John R. Brazelton. The last 5 served with the 24th Indiana volunteers.
  Included also is the discharge of John Watkins, Dec. 31, 1863, from that regiment, signed by John F. Grill, major.
- Deeds of land and land grants in Gibson County
  Among the land grants is one to William Howe, August 1, 1837, signed Martin Van Buren by Abraham Van Buren, secretary, and three grants, October 15, 1853, and June 18, 1856, to Joseph Devin and Joseph J. Kirkman signed by Joseph A. Wright, governor of Indiana.
- Samuel Hall papers
- Miscellaneous papers
  - Partnership agreement, April 5, 1849
    Between Kirkman and James Goodman for the raising of hogs in Gibson County.
  - Kirkman's commission as sheriff of Gibson County, Aug. 21, 1850; Signed by Joseph A. Wright, governor of Indiana.
  - Excise tax receipts to Kirkman and, 1864; 1865
  - Letter from J. T. and G. A. Coolidge of Evansville, Aug 1, 1873
    Concerns a request for aid in meeting a financial obligation.
  - Two pardons to Matthew Tibits and Samuel McAfee, convicted of robbery in Gibson County, Sept. 17, 1840; Signed by David Wallace, governor of Indiana.